# Yannis Fragoulis Platform Engineer

yannis.fragoulis@gmail.com +30 6932326895 Athens, Greece

## **Profile**

I have been working as a software engineer for 12+ years on applications and tools, in many different roles and stacks. I focus on creating robust and reliable applications and infrastructure. I drive products that are either consumer or developer facing, with the same principles regarding architecture, api, security, stability, monitoring, alerting, testing and deployment.

## Skills at a glance



## **Professional Experience**

May 2020 - present

## **Platform Engineer**

Skroutz 🗷

As part of the Platform team, working with DevOps principles, I focus on creating solid infrastructure for company applications to run, as well as, provide the right tools for developers to work with. Some notable projects are:

- The setup of the CI pipeline that uses Jenkins, Github Actions and custom integration services.
- The containerization of the core product.
- The delivery of production-quality data daily, for developers to work with.

Stack consists of: debian (on-premise hosts), puppet, docker, haproxy, mariadb, redis, elasticsearch, mongodb, memcached, nomad, consul, (virtualization), ruby, go, python, shell, github runners.

April 2017 - May 2020

#### **Software Engineer Technical Lead**

Skroutz 🗷

As a tech-lead of a small tools-oriented team, I continued working on a very broad variety of tasks and responsibilities and mentored junior developers into what I believe is good software engineering practices.

April 2015 – April 2017

#### **Software Engineer**

Skroutz 🗷

- Developed a plethora of in-house tools and office automations.
- Developed the product's integration with the ERP.
- Performed a variety of tasks and contributions to the core product and other product-related tools.

Tools of choice were ruby, ruby on rails (framework), mariadb, redis, mongodb, git.

## February 2012 – March 2015

#### **Full-stack Web Developer**

National Documentation Centre

I was tasked with developing the new version the NDC's main products called ABEKT (Integrated Library System) with php, yii (framework), twig, phpunit, javascript (jquery, knockout, angular), postgres, redis, mongodb, git.

## February 2011 –

#### **Full-stack Web Developer**

December 2011

MSLeague

I was part of a very small team developing an ambitious online fantasy-football game with php, yii (framework), javascript (jquery), css and mysql.

## October 2008 – October 2009

#### **Tools Programmer**

The Creative Assembly 🛮

Worked on Total War: Empire and Total War: Napoleon.

As part of the tools team, I contributed in the development of several tools including the asset manager and the campaign editor, with c++, stl, c#, windows api, perforce.

## May 2006 – September 2007

#### **Full-stack Web Developer**

Sentel

Developed on-demand customer websites with php, mysql, javascript (jquery), css, svn.

#### **Education**

#### 2007 - 2008

### **MSc in Games Programming**

**University of Hull** 

Curriculum consisted of (non-exhaustive):

- C++ Programming and Design
- Real-Time Graphics
- Simulation and Artificial Intelligence
- Development Projects
  - https://youtu.be/KhtbUltT168
  - https://youtu.be/MSuIGHds86E
  - https://youtu.be/KdV2ulvqNGw
  - https://github.com/jfragoulis/dissertation-adaptive-aisem3/blob/master/README.md

#### 2002 - 2007

#### **Ptychion in Informatics**

**Panepistimion Pireos**